Periyanayaki Ananthan

Email: nayakinaveen@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 9500726062

Career Objective

To work in a professional and competent atmosphere that enables me to cope with emerging trends and technologies to widen the spectrum of my knowledge. I look forward to an existing and challenging career.

Professional Summary

- Having 3 years of IT experience in Java Development
- Completed Full Stack Developer certification in JAVA technology
- Completed internship in Cognizant Technology Solution
- Involved in various phases of Software Development Life Cycle using **Agile** Methodology and attended various **Scrum** meetings
- Hands on experience in Core Java, JSP, Spring MVC, spring boot and Hibernate
- Comfortable with SQL/MySQL database
- Willing to work on latest technologies

Experience summary

- Worked as a programmer Analyst Trainee, at Cognizant Technology Solution, Coimbatore from Jan 2019 – June 2020
- Worked as a Programmer Analyst, at Cognizant Technology Solution, Coimbatore from June 2020 to July 2021
- Working as a Software Engineer, at Larsen & Toubro Infotech, Chennai from July 2021 to till now.

Technical Expertise

Languages : Java, JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap, CSS

Database : SQL, MYSQL

Frameworks : Spring, Spring boot, Hibernate

• Tools : Eclipse, STS, JIRA, GIT, Visual Studio code and Postman

• Operating systems : Windows

Project 1: Ministry Of Corporate Affairs

Client: Indian Government **Role:** Software Engineer

The Government of India (GOI) has been making efforts on several fronts to improve the investment climate in the country by simplifying the procedures for grant of approvals, by reducing the delays, by reengineering the regulatory processes prescribed under various legislations etc. As a result, starting a business in India has become considerably easier since launching Simplified Proform for Incorporating Company Electronically (SPICe+) form. As a part of initiatives of 'Ease of Doing Business' MCA is contemplating to facilitate the stakeholders in opening a bank account at the time of Incorporating a

Duration: July 2021 – Till Date

Company while filing e-form SPICe+(Incorporation form). MCA in collaboration with Banks is reforming the procedure of applying for company incorporation so that Bank account number can also be issued through SPICe+form only.

Tools: Eclipse, SSCD, WinSCP, DBeaver

Job Responsibility

- Worked as JAVA Developer
- Developed and Maintained Rest web service based on the client requirement
- Deployed web service on the server
- Worked on new Implementations and enhancements of existing web services

Project 2: BART 4D Upgrade

Client: Liberty Mutual Insurance **Role:** Programmer Analyst

BART is the Billing and Receivable Tracking System used to manage premium, loss, audit, and retro receivable transactions on business accounts. The GRS Billing division of Liberty Mutual is going to enhance BART to upgrade the version of 4D from 15 to version 17, rewrite 4D plugins with Java Web services and 64 bit DLL compilation of existing C plugin codes and would like to proceed with a phase of work designed to develop, test and release to production.

Duration: Nov 19 – July 19

Duration: July 19 - Sep 19

Tools: 4D V15 & V17, Visual Studio code, Eclipse

Job Responsibility

- Worked as JAVA and 4D Developer
- Involved WSIT approach development in open VMS server
- Developed SOAP web service and deployed in the ACMS server
- Invoked SOAP web service from 4D to replace existing C/C++ plugin

Project 3: Mentor on Demand

Client: CTS

Role: Programmer Analyst Trainee

This Software System lets users search for a Mentor for a specific Technical Course, User can search, select, propose & finalize a Mentor of his Choice, post which Training gets started.

Tools: STS, Visual Studio code

Job Responsibility

- Designed view part using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JAVA script
- Implemented database connectivity using Spring Boot and Hibernate framework to work upon different modules
- Used MySQL server for database connectivity
- Used Maven to add dependencies required for the project

- Used GIT for version control
- Created Rest web service using spring boot
- Development of Technical Design Document
- Performed code maintenance and build activity for all enhancement/implementation
- Minor code changes and Enhancement done in 4D
- Analyzed existing application and found deprecated command in 4D
- Created test plan document and performed unit testing, integration testing, performance testing and regression testing

Duration: Feb 19 – April 19

- Identified the root cause of bugs and resolved complex bugs in the BART applications
- Used JIRA to handle software development issues

Project 4: Medex Medical Center

Client: CTS

Role: Programmer Analyst Trainee

Medex Medical Center application enables patients and doctors to book and manage appointments. The project has been designed in JAVA Servlet technology and consists of MySQL servers which act as the database for the project. The mainly consists of three types of users. The patient can book, view and cancel their appointment. The doctor can check their appointments and patient's details. The admin can generate report such as number of patients, number of doctors, etc. The system is manipulated successfully using JAVA servlet technology and MySQL server.

Tools: Eclipse, Visual Studio code

Job Responsibility

- Analyzed the requirement for medex medical center from SRS document shared by cognizant
- Developed view part for patient module using JSP, JavaScript, CSS, Ajax and HTML
- Developed **Java Beans** and helper classes to communicate with the presentation tier using controller servlets and JSPs
- Involved in designing **Spring MVC** application and **Hibernate** to design module structure

Strengths

- Positive attitude and continuous learning
- Ability to accomplish challenging tasks
- Analytical thinking
- Problem-Solving/Innovative

Education

• Completed Bachelor of Engineering (ComputerScience) from Kongu Engineering College, Erode in the year 2019 with an aggregate of 80%